ah
we're recording audio yep we're
recording audio
[Music]
all right so today is going to be one of
what i hope is
many other front porch
product reviews now to start this one
off
if you saw or clicked on this or clicked
on the title
you may already know that this video is
about the orvis
tough shell suit they come with pants
and a jacket
if you buy both and i want to let you
know
orvis has not sponsored this i bought
these on my own accord
now full disclosure i am on their guide
program so i did get a discount on these
as a guide
but i did buy them with my own money
to start with i'm going to tell you a
little story
i have had this suit for
i bought it for montana trip for the
montana trip
last year and i missed out on getting
the opportunity to use it
because it showed up a little late my
fault for not planning ahead
but i did have it to take to south
dakota with me and luckily for me
there weren't many days that got overly
wet we had a few days that were snowy
and cold
and i will say that this did a great job
of blocking the wind
and i stayed pretty warm overall wearing
this because it was kind of like a
it could rain it could snow it's going
to be cold as hell and it sure was
but suit did well but i haven't really
had an opportunity to truly
test test the waterproofing until this
last weekend now
i was judging at a hunt test in north
central missouri
and it literally rained from about
8 30 in the morning until three o'clock
in the afternoon when we finished
i was riding a four-wheeler and
getting off walking through the field
getting back
on driving back up picking up the next
dogs and we made a loop
continuous pretty much all day long and
when i wasn't actively
watching dogs and handlers work i got to
just
stand in the rain and wait for the next
set of dogs to show up
so this jacket has a number of different
features
for those of you that want the short
answer this jacket
and pant combo is fantastic if you are
looking for rain gear
looking for upland gear that can be
utilized as rain gear as well
go and get you some for those of you
that want the rest of the details tune
in
and if this is your first time to the
channel guys hit that subscribe button
give us a thumbs up and if you already
use this
let's hear a shout out in the comments
below saying how much you like
the orvis tough shell jacket now some of
the cool things that this jacket has
um the hood allows it to cinch up here
you've got cinches on either side these
cinches were pretty beneficial
for kind of keeping that down over my
hat a little bit
and that allowed me to be able to keep
the rain out of my face
the hood did a good job keeping that
rain that was kind of driving from a
sideways at times direction
off of my face directly you have
big zippers i'm going to show
these big zippers are
there's another zipper in here because
it is a two-way zipper
which is kind of cool come out of there
a big
two-way zipper pull this guy all the way
down and
it zips all the way up and then you can
follow up with if you need
a little extra breathing room down below
you have the ability to do that
big magnets in the pockets
the magnet open the magnet back closed
then you have on the side here you
actually have another pocket that you
can tuck your hands in
all of the inside of these pockets are
like a really soft
lining so it feels nice when your hands
are frozen and pruned like
they were this weekend because they
don't wear gloves why would anybody wear
gloves
you have pockets up here too that
fall into the waterproof category that
you can tuck extra things into
and then if it starts to warm up on you
you have full underarm vents which this
is a thing that orvis does with quite a
few other jackets
but we have that full ventilation there
and then last but not least you actually
have a big pocket in the back that i've
actually utilized for
dead birds i don't know if that's what
it's there for but
it worked great for that and it opens on
both sides
so that being said this is a brief
look at the jacket now for this story
specifically
i had the opportunity to wear this like
i said
in a torrential downpour well it rained
on and off it was kind of a light misty
kind of just enough and then a real
steady
slow soaking rain
my upper half was completely dry
underneath this jacket when it was
raining from 8 8 30
until about 3 o'clock in the afternoon
completely dry
underneath the jacket portion now the
pants
these pants have
[Music]
zip pockets they also have vents so if
you need to get to your inside pockets
and they have their like set zip pockets
here
and a zip back pocket for your wallet
all these pockets zip
and those zipped in liner portions stay
very waterproof as well a lot of times
zippers seams things like that are where
they're going to blow out first on you
or get
wet first on you then you have kind of a
brush guard
type of tough material on the outside
here
and then they buckle at the bottom
for your cuffs and they zip up so you
can kind of get your boots on and off a
little easier
now i wearing these pants i'm sitting on
a four-wheeler and right here i had my
cell phone
and right here i had my wallet and these
portions
that were rubbing on the inside of the
pants
uh all day and kind of having that
constant pressure against the material
all day long i ended up leaking through
right here and right here in the exact
same spots
and it was at it was probably about
1 30 between 1 30 and 2
that i could tell yeah my pockets are
starting to get a little bit wet right
here
every other portion of my pants were
completely dry
and i believe that my mistake was having
that
wallet and cell phone in there rubbing
but
they lasted an incredible incredible
amount of time
in the rain i don't think anything aside
from a true plastic bag
is going to be 100 waterproof for the
entire day
but the fact that this isn't a plastic
bag means that it's
breathable you look at the inside all of
these seams
are reinforced as well as this is a
really soft
breathable lining and it's comfortable
to wear
now if you want to take a closer look
here at the front part of the jacket
and then at the sleeves
and then at the other front part of the
jacket
folks i wore this almost an entire
guiding season
and this is a two-year-old jacket that
looks
basically brand new this stuff is
ridiculous it has held up extremely well
and i end up utilizing it as a jacket
anytime i'm going someplace where it
might potentially rain
because it looks nice enough and i'll
throw it on here
it looks nice enough to just be
a jacket that you would wear to go
someplace
you know how to eat or to do whatever
else not some kind of rain jacket
or not a like i was talking about when
we went up fishing all the guys up there
were
grundens or however you say it exactly
but grundan's i believe
but this jacket just looks nice does it
look like ah that's a rubber bag which
is what those
they were a heavy duty rubber um all of
the suits that the fishing guys were up
there and i understand i mean they're in
water constantly and it did keep you dry
underneath of it
but there was in no way shape or form
breathability there
so i'm gonna say all in all i absolutely
love
the orvis tough shell jacket and pants
combo and if you're looking for
something to add to your
closet for the upland aspect of things
that can keep you dry
either in a rainy hunting day or
even anybody that's hunted in the grouse
woods this stuff i believe is going to
hold up well for you
where you've got those completely dew
covered leaves and trees
that no matter if it's raining or not
you come out of that sucker completely
soaked
to the bone even when it's not raining
outside just because of how much you do
gets held on all the leaves and
everything you're walking through so if
you're looking for something
definitely check out the orvis upland
tough shell
jacket and pants i'm the guy with the
pink gun and we will see you
in the next video
you